First make it work. Then, make it beautiful. Then, make it fast. — BackType



About

I'm a Fullstack Software Engineer with strong product, team play and technology focus. I thrive on joining project teams to take on challenges, build solutions, and grow together. You can find me on linkedin.com/in/killian, github.com/iki, fb.com/iki23 and @jankillian.

Skills

+ Highlights: • 18 years of development experience, agile process, owning the outcomes

- Architecture design, technological expertise, algorithms, security, performance
- Building dev stacks, component libraries, monorepos and npm/pypi packages
- Asynchronous full-remote team collaboration across different time zones

Technologies: • Node.js / TypeScript / Python backend, GraphQL/REST API design, OWASP

- Next.js / React TypeScript frontend, Apollo GraphQL, Material-UI / Ant Design
 SQL/NoSQL data modelling, PostgreSQL, Redis, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB
- GCP / AWS / Azure, GitHub/GitLab CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Shell, Rust

Languages: Czech (native), English (advanced)

Experience

Software Engineer

2020-2022

OAK'S LAB

Ref: Theo Dluhy-Smith, COO & Founder

Developed backends and frontends (80/20) on agile startup projects in full-remote mode

- Designed and developed backend architecture, data models, services, API and CI/CD in TypeScript, Node.js, Apollo GraphQL, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Redis, Google Cloud Run, Firebase, GitHub Actions
- Setup and developed frontend stacks and component systems in React, Material-UI, Ant Design
- Co-developed the MPV and developed Braintree / Tilled payment gateways integration on Crave
- Developed structured text extractor and parser for complex loan agreements (docx) on Simyra

Software Consultant

2019

SABO Mobile IT

Ref: Pavel Zdeněk, Solution Architect

Prototyped GraphQL migration of complex Audi digital planning assistant application

- Developed TypeScript GraphOL backend on top of existing MSSOL database with .NET REST API
- Built containerized prototype environment and lead migration workshop for the development team

Software Engineer

2017-2018

PwC — The Experience Center (Digital Accelerator)

Ref: Andreas Leicher, Agile Architect

Developed rapid agile applications in a full-remote team

- Co-developed frontends with React, GraphQL, Recharts, Material-UI, Swift and ARKit
- Co-developed tech stacks, GraphQL API tests and DP/ML pipeline (Python, PubSub, MongoDB)

Software Engineer

2016-2017

Stories BI (acquired by Workday)

Ref: Peter Fedoročko, Founder, Head of Engineering

Co-developed Augmented Analytics frontend with React, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, HighCharts

Software Engineer

2013-2016

Salsita Software

Ref: Roman Kaspar, Director of Engineering

Developed web applications with React, Redux, Angular, Flask, REST, RAML and MySQL

- Co-developed Balfour MyYear photo manager with React, Redux, SVG
- Developed Balfour Reporting backend and frontend with Python, Flask, MySQL, Angular, HighCharts
- Developed Angular core for SmartBear SaaS platform and AlertSite service
- Developed mobile HTML5 Angular apps for Monterosa and major british TV's

Head of Software Development

Netmail (expanded to Revolgy)

Ref: Bohuslav Dohnal, Managing Director

Lead development projects using Python, Google App Engine and Google Apps

- Developed Google App Engine Python backends and REST APIs
- · Developed tasks to synchronize Google Apps users, calendars, documents and document changes

Software Developer

2010-2011

2012-2013

Multiple startups and customers

Ref: Tomáš Bílý, MFF UK Researcher and Developer

Developed projects using Python, Linux and Google App Engine

- Developed prototype of p2p cloud VPN node management with Python, MongoDB, Ubuntu
- Developed prototypes of REST API backends on Google App Engine

Software Developer

2005-2009

Commerzbank

Ref: Ryan McGloin, Local Head ADS

Developed Intranet applications, CI, security tests, tools for reporting, integration and management

- Lead development of Intranet CMS applications in Firstspirit, Java, Jython, Beanshell
- Analyzed e-banking and server infrastructure migration to the in-house managed server platform
- Setup testing environment and SUSE Linux, WebSphere / JBoss, Oracle / Sybase infrastructure
- Developed reporting/integration/management tools in Python, Shell, Connect:Direct
- Co-developed the Application Security Test Concept based on OWASP

IT&eB Executive

2002-2004

Wyeth (acquired by Pfizer)

Ref: Vladimír Chmela, CFO

Responsible for IT of Czech branch in a global network

- Planned budget and managed assets, suppliers and services
- Managed Novell NetWare 5.1, GroupWise 5.5, Windows 2k and S&M, F&A, R&D applications
- Reshaped network for global setup compliancy, cooperated in merge into global NDS
- Implemented global ZENworks management, supported global WAN, RAS, ITC and eB solutions
- Coordinated local JDE implementation, network infrastructure upgrade and country intranet setup

MIS Technician

1999-2000

TRW (acquired by ZF)

Ref: Shahed Jamal Ashraf, CFO

Responsible for Brain XPPS production planning and control system, co-responsible for IT

- Managed XPPS on AS/400, provided data reports for F&A, logistics and warehouse management
- Managed Novell NetWare 4.11/5.0 network with global NDS, GroupWise, WAN, EDI, RAS solutions
- Coordinated warehouse inventories with CFO

User Support Technician (Civil Service)

1998-1999

University of Economics

Ref: Jan Havlíček, Support Manager

Supported 1500+ employees in a 3-member team

- Installed new hardware and software, reimplemented image based workstation deployment
- Cooperated in LAN/MAN/NetWare maintenance and setting up a new college network

Network Administrator

1996-2002

H-Media

Ref: Michal Ouzký, Technical Manager

Responsible for IT

• Implemented and managed Novell NetWare 4.11/5.1 network with ZENWorks, Windows 95/98/NT, Internet, e-mail, backup, security and data exchange solutions

Network Administrator

1994-1997

Billboard (acquired by Akzent / BigBoard)

Ref: Štěpán Hutla, Technical Director

Responsible for IT

- Setup Novell NetWare 3.12/4.11 network with Windows 3.1/95, Internet, e-mail, backup, security
- Managed development of campaign building client application

Network Administrator (Scholarship Activity)

1994-1995

Faculty of Mathematics and Physics at Charles University (MFF UK)

Co-administered Novell NetWare 3.11 computing lab network

Education

Secondary and University Education

Gymnázium Korunní - Zborovská 1990-1994

Specialization: Mathematics
Degree earned: Maturita (General Certificate of Education)

Faculty of Mathematics and Physics at Charles University (MFF UK)

1994-1997

Study branch: Master Study (MSc.) of Computer Science

Interrupted in the fourth semester due to time constraints with 2 parallel jobs (above)